[
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{31 - 2\\sqrt{228}}$",
    "answer": "$- 2 \\sqrt{3} + \\sqrt{19}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{31 - 2\\sqrt{228}}$<br>我們知道 $31 = 19 + 12$ 且 $228 = 19 \\times 12$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(19 + 12) - 2\\sqrt{19 \\times 12}}$<br>這是 $(- 2 \\sqrt{3} + \\sqrt{19})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $- 2 \\sqrt{3} + \\sqrt{19}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{29 + 2\\sqrt{180}}$",
    "answer": "$3 + 2 \\sqrt{5}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{29 + 2\\sqrt{180}}$<br>我們知道 $29 = 20 + 9$ 且 $180 = 20 \\times 9$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(20 + 9) + 2\\sqrt{20 \\times 9}}$<br>這是 $(3 + 2 \\sqrt{5})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $3 + 2 \\sqrt{5}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{19 + 2\\sqrt{60}}$",
    "answer": "$2 + \\sqrt{15}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{19 + 2\\sqrt{60}}$<br>我們知道 $19 = 15 + 4$ 且 $60 = 15 \\times 4$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(15 + 4) + 2\\sqrt{15 \\times 4}}$<br>這是 $(2 + \\sqrt{15})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $2 + \\sqrt{15}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{42 + 2\\sqrt{437}}$",
    "answer": "$\\sqrt{19} + \\sqrt{23}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{42 + 2\\sqrt{437}}$<br>我們知道 $42 = 23 + 19$ 且 $437 = 23 \\times 19$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(23 + 19) + 2\\sqrt{23 \\times 19}}$<br>這是 $(\\sqrt{19} + \\sqrt{23})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $\\sqrt{19} + \\sqrt{23}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{18 - 2\\sqrt{56}}$",
    "answer": "$-2 + \\sqrt{14}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{18 - 2\\sqrt{56}}$<br>我們知道 $18 = 14 + 4$ 且 $56 = 14 \\times 4$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(14 + 4) - 2\\sqrt{14 \\times 4}}$<br>這是 $(-2 + \\sqrt{14})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $-2 + \\sqrt{14}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{20 + 2\\sqrt{96}}$",
    "answer": "$2 \\sqrt{2} + 2 \\sqrt{3}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{20 + 2\\sqrt{96}}$<br>我們知道 $20 = 12 + 8$ 且 $96 = 12 \\times 8$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(12 + 8) + 2\\sqrt{12 \\times 8}}$<br>這是 $(2 \\sqrt{2} + 2 \\sqrt{3})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $2 \\sqrt{2} + 2 \\sqrt{3}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{20 + 2\\sqrt{99}}$",
    "answer": "$3 + \\sqrt{11}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{20 + 2\\sqrt{99}}$<br>我們知道 $20 = 11 + 9$ 且 $99 = 11 \\times 9$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(11 + 9) + 2\\sqrt{11 \\times 9}}$<br>這是 $(3 + \\sqrt{11})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $3 + \\sqrt{11}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{29 + 2\\sqrt{168}}$",
    "answer": "$2 \\sqrt{2} + \\sqrt{21}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{29 + 2\\sqrt{168}}$<br>我們知道 $29 = 21 + 8$ 且 $168 = 21 \\times 8$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(21 + 8) + 2\\sqrt{21 \\times 8}}$<br>這是 $(2 \\sqrt{2} + \\sqrt{21})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $2 \\sqrt{2} + \\sqrt{21}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{28 - 2\\sqrt{147}}$",
    "answer": "$- \\sqrt{7} + \\sqrt{21}$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{28 - 2\\sqrt{147}}$<br>我們知道 $28 = 21 + 7$ 且 $147 = 21 \\times 7$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(21 + 7) - 2\\sqrt{21 \\times 7}}$<br>這是 $(- \\sqrt{7} + \\sqrt{21})^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $- \\sqrt{7} + \\sqrt{21}$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  },
  {
    "question": "化簡：$\\sqrt{29 + 2\\sqrt{208}}$",
    "answer": "$\\sqrt{13} + 4$",
    "explanation": "原式 = $\\sqrt{29 + 2\\sqrt{208}}$<br>我們知道 $29 = 16 + 13$ 且 $208 = 16 \\times 13$<br>所以原式 = $\\sqrt{(16 + 13) + 2\\sqrt{16 \\times 13}}$<br>這是 $(\\sqrt{13} + 4)^2$ 的平方根<br>因此，原式 = $\\sqrt{13} + 4$",
    "size": 2,
    "difficulty": "MEDIUM"
  }
]